Bendix, Reinhard; Papers ger021
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
Reinhard Bendix Papers
1929-1998
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
ger021
13.67 cubic ft.
The bulk of the collection consists of Bendix's writings and the materials used by him for research purposes as well as for his courses in political and social sciences. This includes a large volume of materials on Max Weber, social stratification, power and authority, bureaucracy, industrialization and large-scale organizations. Bendix' files contain correspondence dealing with his career at the University of California, Berkeley and include materials pertaining to controversies at the university and within the Department of Sociology, as well as student issues and recommendations. Also present in the collection are a number of files dealing with individuals and issues connected with both the American Sociological Association and the International Sociological Association.
Biographical Sketch
Reinhard Bendix was born in Berlin, Germany in 1916 and received his formal education at the Gymnasium in Berlin from 1927-1933. After graduation, Bendix spent a year in England where he attended school and worked on a farm in Welwyn Garden City, in the vicinity of London. Upon his return to Germany in 1935, he found employment as a clerk in the export firm of L. Hecht & Co. and later (1937) in the Palaestina Treuhandstelle in Paltreu, Berlin. It was also during these same years that Reinhard became a member of both HaShomer HaZair and the anti-Fascist underground organization Neu Beginnen. In 1938, he was forced to flee Hitler-Germany and immigrated to the U.S.
With the help of family friends, Bendix immigrated to the United States in September of 1938 and immediately enrolled in undergraduate studies at the University of Chicago. During the years from 1938 to 1946, he attended the University of Chicago on full scholarship, receiving his B.A. in 1941, his M.A. in 1943, and his Ph.D. in Sociology in 1946, studying under Professor Charles Merriam. During this time, he also met and married Jane Walstrum (1940).
After completing his studies, Reinhard Bendix spent one year at the University of Colorado in Boulder, but relocated to California and the University of California, Berkeley in 1947. He became a member of the Faculty of the Department of Sociology, and later the Department of Political Science, and remained at Berkeley until his retirement. Bendix's main research interests centered around the areas of comparative social stratification, political and industrial sociology, and the history of social theory. He was also instrumental in introducing and popularizing the works of Max Weber among American social scientists. His works include Class, Status and Power (with S.M. Lipset, 1953; 1966), Work and Authority in Industry (1956; 1974), Social Mobility in Industry (also with S.M. Lipset, 1959); Max Weber: An Intellectual Portrait (1960), Nation Building and Citizenship (1964; 1976), Kings or People: Power and the Mandate to Rule (1978), and From Berlin to Berkeley: German Jewish Identities (1986 autobiography), as well as over sixty contributions to professional journals.
Chronology of Events:
1916 Born on February 25 in Berlin to Ludwig (1877-1954) and Else Henschel Bendix (1883-1968).
1927-1933 Attended the Gymnasium in Berlin.
1934 Attended school in the United Kingdom and worked on a farm outside of London (Welwyn Garden City).
1935-1937 Clerk in the Berlin export firm, L. Hecht & Co. Member of the group Neu Beginnen and HaShomer HaZair.
1937-1938 Clerk at the Palaestina Treuhandstelle in Paltreu, Berlin.
1938 Emigrated to the U.S. in September.
1938-1946 Attended the University of Chicago with full scholarships.
1940 Married Jane Walstrum on July 5.
1941 Received a B.A. from the University of Chicago.
1941-1943 Research Assistant of the Social Science Research Committee of the University of Chicago.
1943 Became an American citizen.
1943 Received M.A. in Sociology from the University of Chicago.
1943-1946 Instructor of Social Science at the University of Chicago.
1946-1947 Assistant Professor of Sociology at the University of Colorado, Boulder.
1947 Received Ph.D. in Sociology from the University of Chicago.
1947-1951 Assistant Professor in the Department of Sociology, University of California, Berkeley.
1948-1950 Member of the Editorial Committee, University of California Press.
1948-1972 Resident Sociologist at Berkeley's Institute of Industrial Relations.
1949 Birth of daughter, Karen.
1949 Assistant Professor, Department of Sociology, Columbia University (Summer session).
1951 Birth of son, Erik.
1951-1956 Associate Professor of Sociology, University of California, Berkeley.
1951-1952 Sociologist, Student Health Service, Cowell Hospital, University of California (psychiatric consultation).
1952-1953 Vice President, Alameda County Mental Health Society.
1953-1954 Fulbright Research Grant, University of Frankfurt, Germany.
1956 Birth of son, John.
1956-1972 Promoted to rank of Full Professor of Sociology, Berkeley.
1958 Winner of the MacIver Award (American Sociological Association) for his book Work and Authority in Industry.
1958-1961 Chairman of the Department of Sociology, University of California, Berkeley.
1961-1962 Received "Reflective Year Fellowship" from Carnegie Corporation for studies in India and Japan.
1963-1964 Vice President of the American Sociological Association.
1964-1965 Visiting Professor of Sociology at the Freie Universität, Berlin and Visiting Fellow at St. Catherine College, Oxford.
1966-1970 Elected Vice President of the International Sociological Association, as well as Corresponding Member of the Deutsche Gesellschaft für Soziologie.
1968-1970 Director of University of California Study Center in Göttingen, Germany.
1969-1970 President of the American Sociological Association.
1971 Fellow of the Nuffield College, Oxford.
1971-1972 Fellow of the Institute for Advanced Study, Princeton.
1971-1974 Permanent Guest Professor of the University of Konstanz, Germany.
1972-1989 Professor of Political Science and Lecturer in the Department of Sociology.
1975-1976 Fellowship from the Woodrow Wilson International Center of Scholars, Washington, D.C. and Guggenheim Fellowship.
1977 Elected to the American Philosophical Society, Philadelphia.
1978 Received honorary doctorate from the University of Leeds, England.
1980 Received honorary doctorate from the University of Mannheim, Germany.
1981 Max Weber Guest Professor at the University of Heidelberg, Germany.
1982-1989 Numerous lectures given throughout the U.S. and Europe.
1991 Died of a heart attack on February 28 in Berkeley, California.
Scope and Contents
The Reinhard Bendix Papers, 1929-1998, consist of 13.67 cu. ft. of materials and are divided into seven series: 1) Autobiographical and biographical materials, 1929-1998; 2) Correspondence files, 1948-1987; 3) Published and unpublished writings of Reinhard Bendix, 1930-1986; 4) Course and lecture notes, 1943-1986; 5) Published and unpublished writings by others; 6) Miscellaneous materials, notes; and 7) Pamphlet collection.
The bulk of the collection consists of Bendix' writings and the materials used by him for research purposes as well as for his courses in political and social sciences. This includes a large volume of materials on Max Weber, social stratification, power and authority, bureaucracy, industrialization and large-scale organizations.
Bendix' files contain correspondence dealing with his career at the University of California, Berkeley and include materials pertaining to controversies at the university and within the Department of Sociology, as well as student issues and recommendations. Also present in the collection are a number of files dealing with individuals and issues connected with both the American Sociological Association and the International Sociological Association.
Arrangement of the Collection
The collection is organized as follows:
Series 1: Autobiographical and Biographical Materials, 1929-1998
Series 2: Correspondence Files, 1948-1987
Series 3: Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Bendix, 1930-1991
Series 4: Course and Lecture Notes, 1943-1986
Series 5: Published and Unpublished Writings by Others
Series 6: Miscellaneous Materials, Notes
Series 7: Pamphlet Collection
Acquisition Information
All items in this manuscript group were donated to the University Libraries, M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, by Reinhard Bendix in 1989 and 1990; additions to the collection were made by John Bendix in 1998, 2014, and 2025.
Access
Access to this record group is unrestricted with the exception of a small number of correspondence files.
Political Science; Sociologists -- United States.; Political scientists -- United States.; Germans -- United States.; Anti-Nazi movement.; Jews -- Germany.; Bureaucracy -- Study and teaching.; Jews -- Germany -- Berlin..; Bendix, Reinhard.; Marx, Karl, 1818-1883.; Weber, Max, 1864-1920.; Bendix, Ludwig, 1877-1954.; Frank, Karl Boromäus, 1893-1969.; Deutsch, Karl.; Geertz, Clifford.; Kirchheimer, Otto.; Lazarsfeld, Karl.; Lowe, Adolph, 1893-; Lipset, Seymour M.; Lynd, Helen.; Waldinger, Ernst, 1896-1970.; Lynd, Robert, 1879-1949.; Merton, Robert King, 1910-2003.; Parsons, Talcott, 1902-1979.; Riesman, David, 1909-2002.; Gruppe Neu Beginnen.; American Sociological Association.; International Sociological Association.; University of Chicago. Department of Sociology.; University of California, Berkeley. Department of Sociology.; University of California, Berkeley. Department of Political Science.
- Autobiographical and Biographical Materials, 1929-1998; 1; 36 file folders
  Scope and Contents
  The first twenty-four folders of this series contain curriculum vitae and publication lists, several early recommendations from Germany, materials by and about Ludwig (father), Else Henschel (mother), and John Bendix (son), and autobiographical statements by Reinhard Bendix, in particular materials pertaining to the autobiography of Reinhard and his father, From Berlin to Berkeley. The remaining folders in the series contain reviews of Bendix' major works.
  - German recommendations and resumé, 1933-1937 (Box 1 (1-Autobiographical and Biographical Materials), Folder 1)
  - Curriculum vitae and list of publications, Undated (Box 1 (1-Autobiographical and Biographical Materials), Folder 2)
  - Honorary degrees, 1978; 1980 (Box 1 (1-Autobiographical and Biographical Materials), Folder 3)
  - Who's who entries, Undated (Box 1 (1-Autobiographical and Biographical Materials), Folder 4)
  - "A Memoir of My Father", 1965; reprint (Box 1 (1-Autobiographical and Biographical Materials), Folder 5)
  - "Rückblicke auf Deutschland. Aufsätze über Wandlungen des Bewußtseins im Zentrum Europas von Johannes Anderegg, Rainer M. Lepsius, Rudolf von Thadden. Herausgegeben und eingeleitet von Reinhard Bendix", 1971 July; typescript (Box 1 (1-Autobiographical and Biographical Materials), Folder 6)
  - "A Trip to East Berlin and Alt-Golm", 1979 May 15-1979 May 16 (Box 1 (1-Autobiographical and Biographical Materials), Folder 7)
  - "A Personal Memoir or How I became an American Sociologist", 1980; typescript (Box 1 (1-Autobiographical and Biographical Materials), Folder 8)
  - From Berlin to Berkeley. Correspondence and documents, 1929-1981 (Box 1 (1-Autobiographical and Biographical Materials), Folder 9)
  - From Berlin to Berkeley. Project description, Undated (Box 1 (1-Autobiographical and Biographical Materials), Folder 10)
  - From Berlin to Berkeley. Table of contents, Introduction, Undated (Box 1 (1-Autobiographical and Biographical Materials), Folder 11)
  - From Berlin to Berkeley. Epilogue, Undated (Box 1 (1-Autobiographical and Biographical Materials), Folder 12)
  - From Berlin to Berkeley, Undated (Box 1 (1-Autobiographical and Biographical Materials), Folder 13)
    Notes.
  - From Berlin to Berkeley. Statistics on German Jews, Undated (Box 1 (1-Autobiographical and Biographical Materials), Folder 14)
  - From Berlin to Berkeley. Background materials, Undated (Box 1 (1-Autobiographical and Biographical Materials), Folder 15)
  - From Berlin to Berkeley. German legal materials, Undated (Box 1 (1-Autobiographical and Biographical Materials), Folder 16)
  - "Dämmerung. Ein Monolog", Undated; typescript (Box 1 (1-Autobiographical and Biographical Materials), Folder 17)
  - Bendix, Else Henschel. "How the critics judged me... Newspaper reviews of my seven years on stage, 1904-1911", Undated; typescript (Box 1 (1-Autobiographical and Biographical Materials), Folder 18)
  - Bendix, Ludwig. Correspondence, 1935; 1953 (Box 1 (1-Autobiographical and Biographical Materials), Folder 19)
  - Bendix, Ludwig. Published bibliography, Undated (Box 1 (1-Autobiographical and Biographical Materials), Folder 20)
  - Bendix, Ludwig. "Rechtspolitische Schriften", Undated; reprint (Box 1 (1-Autobiographical and Biographical Materials), Folder 21)
  - Bendix, Ludwig. "Tragik des Berufsrichters und der Rechtsunterworfenen in Deutschland", Undated (Box 1 (1-Autobiographical and Biographical Materials), Folder 22)
  - Bendix, John. Correspondence, 1985-1986; Undated (Box 1 (1-Autobiographical and Biographical Materials), Folder 23)
  - Bendix, John. "The Non-Belonging of the Foreign Worker", 1986; photocopy (Box 1 (1-Autobiographical and Biographical Materials), Folder 24)
  - "Comparison in the Work of Reinhard Bendix", 1998; photocopy (Box 1 (1-Autobiographical and Biographical Materials), Folder 24)
  - Reviews of works by Reinhard Bendix, 1.26 (Box 1 (1-Autobiographical and Biographical Materials), Folder 25-36)
    - Higher Civil Servants in American Society, 1949 (Box 1 (1-Autobiographical and Biographical Materials), Folder 25)
      Reviews.
    - Work and Authority in Industry, 1956; 1974 (Box 1 (1-Autobiographical and Biographical Materials), Folder 26)
      Reviews, correspondence.
    - Herrschaft und Industriearbeit, 1960 (Box 1 (1-Autobiographical and Biographical Materials), Folder 27)
    - Max Weber: An Intellectual Portrait, 1960 (Box 1 (1-Autobiographical and Biographical Materials), Folder 28)
    - Nation Building and Citizenship, 1964 (Box 1 (1-Autobiographical and Biographical Materials), Folder 29)
    - Embattled Reason, 1970 (Box 1 (1-Autobiographical and Biographical Materials), Folder 30)
    - Scholarship and Partnership: Essays on Max Weber (with Guenther Roth), 1971 (Box 1 (1-Autobiographical and Biographical Materials), Folder 31)
    - Sociology and Ideology, 1970 (Box 1 (1-Autobiographical and Biographical Materials), Folder 32)
      Review.
    - Force, Fate, and Freedom, 1984 (Box 1 (1-Autobiographical and Biographical Materials), Folder 33)
    - Von Berlin nach Berkeley, 1985 (Box 1 (1-Autobiographical and Biographical Materials), Folder 34)
    - Kings or People, 1979 (Box 1 (1-Autobiographical and Biographical Materials), Folder 35)
    - Kings or People (Könige oder Volk), Undated (Box 1 (1-Autobiographical and Biographical Materials), Folder 36)
- Correspondence Files, 1948-1987; 2; 163 file folders
  This series contains correspondence with colleagues and administrators at the University of California, Berkeley, as well as with other scholars in the field and include: Bert F. Hoselitz, René König, Seymour Martin Lipset, Talcott Parsons, David Rapoport, David Riesman, Stein Rokkan, Guenther Roth, Wolfgang Schluchter, Reinhart Schneider and Edward Shils. The series also contains a number of files dealing with a controvery inside the International Sociological Association (1954-1956), and include correspondence with: Tom Bottomore, T. H. Marshall, Robert C. Angell, Kurt H. Wolff, Nelson Foote, Alfred McClung Lee, Stein Rokkan, and Clark Kerr.
  Arrangement
  Arranged alphabetically.
  - A -- recommendations and miscellaneous correspondence, Undated (Box 1 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 37)
  - Adams, James L., 1952 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 38)
  - American Academy of Arts and Sciences, 1973-1980 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 38)
  - American Philosophical Society, 1977-1978 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 39)
  - Amnesty International, 1987 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 39)
  - Andrews, John A. Y., 1980-1981 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 39)
  - Association for Asian Studies (Journal of Asian Studies), 1965-1966 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 40)
  - B -- recommendations and miscellaneous correspondence - [RESTRICTED], Undated (Box 1 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 41)
    Conditions Governing Access
    Must consult archivist before viewing this material.
  - Baumann, Zygmunt, 1978-1983 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 42)
  - Baylis, Thomas, 1980 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 42)
  - Bell, Daniel, 1973 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 43)
  - Bell, Wendell, 1976 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 43)
  - Ben-David, Joseph, 1978 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 43)
  - Berg, Ellen Ziskind, 1980; 1984 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 44)
  - Berger, Bennett M., 1983-1984 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 44)
  - Bergesen, Albert, 1977; 1981 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 45)
  - Binder, Leonard, 1969-1970 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 45)
  - Bird, Richard, 1975 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 46)
  - Bisson, Thomas, 1978 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 46)
  - Blalock, Hubert, 1979 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 46)
  - Blumberg, Paul, 1978 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 47)
  - Blumer, Herbert, 1951 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 47)
  - Bogacz, Theodore, 1975-1980 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 48)
  - Bonham, Gary, 1982-1984 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 48)
  - Bonnell, Victoria, 1978-1983 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 49)
  - Brand, Coenraad, 1971-1972 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 50)
  - Braudel, Fernand, 1976 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 50)
  - Braungart, Richard (Dick), 1986-1987 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 51)
  - Bruneau, Thomas C., 1980 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 51)
  - Bry, Ernst, 1978 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 52)
  - Bry, Gerhard, 1978-1979 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 52)
  - C - D -- recommendations and miscellaneous correspondence, Undated (Box 1 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 53)
  - Callaghy, Thomas M., 1978-1980 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 54)
  - Cavalli, Luciano, 1981-1982 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 54)
  - Center for Advanced Study in the Behavioral Sciences, 1976 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 54)
  - Chernin, Milton, 1977 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 55)
  - Collins, Randall, 1980 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 55)
  - Committee on Scholarly Communication with the People's Republic of China, 1982-1983 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 56)
  - Conrad, Dietrich, 1990; 1979 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 56)
  - Craig, Gordon, 1979 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 56)
  - DaPazzo, François, 1977 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 57)
  - Daito, Eisuke, 1979 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 57)
  - Dassin, Joan, 1977 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 57)
  - Dean, Shirley, 1981-1982 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 58)
  - Delany, William, 1972 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 58)
  - Demerath, Jay, 1985 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 58)
  - Desjardins, Barbara, 1977-1981 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 58)
  - Dickey, Laurence, 1981 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 59)
  - Diefendorf, Jeffry M., 1980 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 59)
  - Dittmer, Lowell, 1987 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 59)
  - Dore, Ronald, 1963 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 59)
  - Eastern Sociological Society (William J. Goode), 1952; 1960 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 60)
  - Easton, David, 1983-1984 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 60)
  - Egan, Alan, 1978 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 60)
  - Ehrmann, Henry, 1977 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 61)
  - Eidlin, Fred, 1980-1983 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 61)
  - Eisenstedt, S.N., 1966 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 61)
  - F - G -- recommendations and miscellaneous correspondence - [RESTRICTED], Undated (Box 1 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 62)
  - Ferkiss, Victor, 1980 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 63)
  - Ferrarotti, Franco, 1965-1966 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 63)
  - Fillinger, Paul (Paul Fillinger Film Productions), 1980 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 64)
  - Fliessbach, Holger, 1980 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 65)
  - Flora, Peter, 1987 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 65)
  - Fügen, Hans Norbert, 1981-1982 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 65)
  - Furniss, Norman, 1985-1986 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 65)
  - Gadgil, D. R. (re: Nation Building and Citizenship), 1963-1964 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 66)
  - Gaines, William L. (The Institute of Foreign Studies), 1977 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 66)
  - Galambos, Louis, 1977-1978 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 67)
  - Gaus, John M., 1948 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 67)
  - Getzler, Israel, 1977-1983 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 68)
  - Giesen, Bernd, 1990 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 68)
  - Glassman, Ronald, 1976-1983 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 68)
  - Glazer, Nathan, 1951; 1977 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 69)
  - Gordon, Richard, 1981 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 69)
  - Graña, César, 1977 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 70)
  - Gray, Hanna Holborn, 1981 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 70)
  - Gress, David, 1982 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 70)
  - Grimshaw, Allen D., 1978 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 71)
  - Guggenheim Fellowship, 1975 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 71)
  - Gum, William L., 1976-1982 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 71)
  - Gustafson, Paul M., 1986 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 71)
  - H - J -- recommendations and miscellaneous correspondence - RESTRICTED, Undated (Box 1 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 72)
  - Haase, Paul, 1979 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 73)
  - Habermas, Jürgen, 1980 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 73)
  - Hall, John R., 1982 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 73)
  - Hekman, Susan J., 1981 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 73)
  - Hennis, Wilhelm, 1978-1986 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 74)
  - Hohmann, Nikolaus, 1985 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 75)
  - Honegger, Claudia, 1980 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 75)
  - Hoselitz, Bert F., 1949-1951 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 75)
  - Howe, Gary Nigel, 1979 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 76)
  - Huff, Toby E., 1982 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 76)
  - Hughes, Jim, 1977 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 77)
  - International Biographical Archives and Dictionary of Central European Emigres, 1933-1945; 1976-1979 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 77)
  - International Sociological Association (Tom Bottomore, T. H. Marshall, Robert C. Angell), 1954-1956 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 78)
  - International Sociological Association (Kurt H. Wolff, Nelson Foote, Alfred McClung Lee, Stein Rokkan, Clark Kerr), 1954-1956 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 79)
  - Correspondence concerning the 1978 meeting of the International Sociological Association, 2.97 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 1-9)
    - International Sociological Association, general, 1976-1977 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 1)